markavip.com 2016-04-08

# Privacy Policy - MarkaVIP

Effective Date: 05/05/2014

This privacy policy applies to [markavip.com](https://www.markavip.com/) owned and operated by MarkaVIP NV, a company duly incorporated, organized and registered under the Belgian law with registered office at Rijnkaai 98, Hangar 26, 2000 Antwerp, Belgium (hereinafter referred to together with its subsidiaries and affiliates as MarkaVIP), in its capacity of controller of the personal data.

This privacy policy describes how MarkaVIP collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: [markavip.com](https://www.markavip.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

MarkaVIP has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. 

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [markavip.com](https://www.markavip.com/) and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

Data protection is a matter of trust and your privacy is important to MarkaVIP. MarkaVIP shall therefore only use your name and other information which relates to you in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy. MarkaVIP will only collect information where it is necessary for MarkaVIP to do so and MarkaVIP will only collect information if it is relevant to its dealings with you.

MarkaVIP will only keep your information for as long as MarkaVIP is either required to by law or as is relevant for the purposes for which it was collected. You can visit the MarkaVIP website and use MarkaVIP’s mobile app (collectively called the “Platform”) and browse without having to register for an Account.

## 1\. Data that MarkaVIP collects

Your personally identifiable data (first name, last name, email, billing information such as credit card number and billing address) is processed by MarkaVIP.

Your data is collected and processed to: 

  * (a) Administer your Account;
  * (b) Process your Orders (including but not limited to delivery of the Products);
  * (c) Verify and carry out financial transactions in relation to payment you make online (including but not limited to payment verification, fraud protection and credit risk reduction);
  * (d) Provide you with the services and information offered through the Platform;
  * (e) Undertake direct marketing;
  * (f) Audit the downloading of data from the Platform;
  * (g) Improve the layout and/or content of the pages of the Platform and customize the Platform for users;
  * (h) identify visitors on the Platform; 
  * (i) Carry out research on MarkaVIP’s users’ demographics; and/or
  * (j) Send you information which MarkaVIP deems you may find useful or which you have requested from MarkaVIP (including information about MarkaVIP’s Products, its newsletters, sales or promotions; information relating to other companies in MarkaVIP’s group or MarkaVIP’s business partners), provided you have indicated that you have not objected to being contacted for these purposes. 

MarkaVIP will use your personal data only for the purposes indicated above.

MarkaVIP mainly does business in the Middle East and most data that it collects and processes is in those countries. By giving your data to MarkaVIP, you agree to it being transferred to its commercial partners, who may be located in a country outside the European Union ("EU") where other standards of data protection might apply, including to companies whose intervention as data processors, acting on behalf and under the control of MarkaVIP, is required to accomplish the purposes indicated above. 

Subject to the above, MarkaVIP will not disclose, sell, rent or exchange such personal data to any other organization or entity, unless you are first notified and expressly agree, or as otherwise required by law. Payments that you make through the Platform will be processed by CyberSource (a Visa company)

Your actual order details may be stored on MarkaVIP’s server but for security reasons cannot be retrieved directly by MarkaVIP. However, you may access this information by logging into your Account on the Platform. There you can:

  * (a) View the details of your Orders that have been completed, those which are open and those which are shortly to be dispatched; and
  * (b) Administer your address details, bank details and any newsletter to which you may have subscribed. 

MarkaVIP draws your attention to the fact that you have the right to access and restrict your data and, where appropriate, request rectification of any incorrect data relating to you. 

The Platform may contain links to other websites not owned or operated by MarkaVIP. Please be aware that MarkaVIP is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites and that this Privacy Policy applies solely to data collected by MarkaVIP.

## 2\. Other uses of your personal information

Subject to obtaining your consent, MarkaVIP may contact you by email with details of other Products. MarkaVIP may use your personal information for direct MarkaVIP related marketing (including opinion and market research). You may, at any moment, opt out by sending an e-mail regarding any questions you may have to [support@markavip.com](mailto:support@markavip.com), or by ordinary mail to the following address.

MarkaVIP - Amman, Jordan P.O Box 42, Alia Housing. T: +96265777711 

MarkaVIP may also send you other information about MarkaVIP, the Platform, MarkaVIP’s Products, sales promotions, MarkaVIP’s newsletter and other information related to other companies in MarkaVIP’s group or MarkaVIP’s business partners. If you would prefer not to receive any of this additional information as detailed in this paragraph (or any part of it) please click the ‘unsubscribe’ link in the newsletter that MarkaVIP sends to you. 

MarkaVIP may further anonymize data about users of the Platform generally and use it for various purposes, including ascertaining the general location of the users and usage of certain aspects of the Platform or a link contained in an email to those registered to receive them, and supplying that anonymized data to third parties such as publishers. However, that anonymized data will not be capable of identifying you personally.

## 3\. Third parties and links

MarkaVIP may pass your details to other companies in MarkaVIP’s group. MarkaVIP may also pass your details to MarkaVIP’s agents and subcontractors to help MarkaVIP with uses of your data as set out in this Privacy Policy. For example, MarkaVIP may use third parties to assist MarkaVIP with delivering Products to you, to help it to collect payments from you, to analyze data and to provide MarkaVIP with marketing or customer service assistance. MarkaVIP may exchange information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. MarkaVIP may transfer MarkaVIP’s databases containing your personal information if MarkaVIP is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information and to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. We may also disclose your personal information, as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect our safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to government request. 

Other than as set out in this Privacy Policy, MarkaVIP shall not sell or disclose your personal data to third parties without obtaining your prior consent unless this is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or unless MarkaVIP is required to do so by law.

The Platform may contain advertising of third parties and links to other sites or frames of other sites. Please be aware that MarkaVIP is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those third parties or other sites, nor for any third party to whom it transfers your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 4\. Use of Facebook and Twitter social plugins

The Platform may use social plugins (“plugins”) provided by the social network facebook.com, operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The plugins are identifiable by a Facebook logo or the notice “Facebook Social Plugin”. 

The Platform may use social plugins (“plugins”) provided by the social network twitter.com, operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”). The plugins are identifiable by a Twitter logo or the notice “Twitter Social Plugin”. 

The Platform may use social plugins (“plugins”) provided by the social network linkedin.com, operated by LinkedIn Ltd., 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“LinkedIn”). The plugins are identifiable by a LinkedIn logo or the notice “LinkedIn Social Plugin”. 

When you visit a page of the Platform that contains a social plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to Facebook and/or Twitter servers. Facebook and Twitter directly transfer the plugin content to your browser which embeds the latter into the Platform, enabling Facebook and Twitter to receive information about your having accessed the respective page of the Platform. For this purpose, the internet address of the visited site (your IP address included) is transferred to a USA-based Facebook and/or Twitter server where the data are stored. This occurs even if you do not have a Facebook or Twitter account or are not logged into Facebook/Twitter at the time.

If you are logged into Facebook, your visit can be assigned to your Facebook account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by clicking “Like”, or entering a comment, the corresponding information is transmitted from your browser directly to Facebook and stored by it. The information can also be published on Facebook, and shown to your Facebook friends.

For information on the purpose and scope of data collection by Facebook/Twitter/ LinkedIn and how it is processed and used, as well as your rights in this respect and settings options for protecting your privacy please visit Facebook’s privacy policy <https://www.facebook.com/fbprivacy>, Twitter's privacy policy (<https://twitter.com/privacy>) or LinkedIn’s privacy policy ([http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)) 

### Single Sign-On

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

### Chat

We use a chat feature to assist you with any general enquiries you may have. If our chat feature is offline we will collect your name and email address so that we may reply to your request. We may require you to provide us with your name and email address, in case we had to come back to you with a reply to enquiry.

## 5\. Cookies

MarkaVIP also collects non-personally identifiable information passively using "cookies" and "action tags".

### 5.1 Cookies

"Cookies" are small text files that are placed on your computer in order to identify your web browser and the activities of your computer on the Platform and other websites. MarkaVIP may use Cookies to allow it to statistically monitor how you are using the Platform to help it improve its online offerings or to determine the popularity of certain content. MarkaVIP furthermore sends a "session cookie" to your computer when you log in to the Platform. These session cookies allow MarkaVIP to recognize if you visit multiple pages during the same browser session, without needing to re-enter your login information multiple times. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. Most browsers offer instructions on how to do so in the "Help" section of the toolbar. Please be aware that for technological reasons if you decline the use of cookies you will be unable to login to the Platform.

### 5.2 Action Tags

"Action tags" also known as web beacons or gif tags, are a web technology used to help track website usage information, such as how many times a specific page has been viewed. Action tags are invisible to you, and any portion of the MarkaVIP Platform, including advertisements, or email sent on MarkaVIP’s behalf, may contain action tags. MarkaVIP may select and use from time to time different third parties to track Platform usage through action tags on the Platform. 

By using cookies and action tags together, MarkaVIP is able to gain valuable information to improve the MarkaVIP Platform and online offerings and measure the effectiveness of the MarkaVIP advertising and marketing campaigns. 

### 5.3 What kind of information is stored in cookies?

The cookies used by MarkaVIP may be used to store any personal information. MarkaVIP’s cookies may be traced back to an individual user with extensive research. Once a cookie is activated, it is given an ID number, which is solely used for internal reference and may be used to identify the user and access personal information, such as your name or IP address. The information MarkaVIP receives from the cookies allows MarkaVIP to assess which pages of the Platform are visited the most and see which products were most popular etc.

### 5.4 Does MarkaVIP use third party cookies?

Cookies from specific business partners are allowed by MarkaVIP for the purpose of tailoring their adverts to your tastes and browsing habits, so cookies from some of MarkaVIP’s partners may be stored on your computer when you visit the Platform. These cookies are temporary/permanent cookies, which will be automatically deleted from your computer at the end of their lifespan. (The data stored is collected at certain times, allowing these companies to see which content has been viewed most frequently. Third party cookies have the sole purpose of allowing MarkaVIP’s partners to advertise products that may interest you.

If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking the links below and following the instructions. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Vizury: [http://web.vizury.com/website/in/opt-out/](https://web.vizury.com/website/in/opt-out/)  
Adroll: [http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1&nt=1&nw=false](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1&nt=1&nw=fals)

Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility companies and service providers may use cookies to enhance the customer's online shopping experience.The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility companies and service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

### 5.5 Declaration of Consent

By using the Platform, I hereby give permission for my user information to be stored on cookie files. I also allow these files to remain on my computer after I have ended my browser session so they may be used upon my next visit to the Platform. I reserve the right to retract this permission by changing my browser setting to refuse cookies. 

## 6\. Log information

### 6.1 General

Every time you visit MarkaVIP, information is sent from your browser to MarkaVIP’s server log files, where it will be saved. The information transferred includes: time and date of visit to the Platform, which pages were viewed, IP address, URL of site that referred you to MarkaVIP, how much information has been stored and which browser you have been using.

The information stored in this log file is then used to improve the shopping experience on the Platform by making MarkaVIP’s navigation more user-friendly, finding errors quickly and directing MarkaVIP’s server’s capacity to where it is needed most. For example, this information allows us to work out MarkaVIP’s busiest times and plan enough server power for those times to keep MarkaVIP’s site running as quickly as possible.

### 6.2 Consent

By using the Platform, I am giving MarkaVIP permission to analyze and use protocol data to develop and optimize their online shop.

## 7\. Security

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@markavip.com](mailto:support@markavip.com)

To ensure secure online payment and security where sensitive personal data is involved, the MarkaVIP Platform uses SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology. For further information, please consult your browser’s security specifications.

## 8\. Consent

By submitting data to MarkaVIP or MarkaVIP’s agent or using the Platform you consent to MarkaVIP’s use of your data in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy including all services provided used by MarkaVIP or third parties to verify your identity.

## 9\. Your rights

If you are concerned about your data you have the right to request access to the personal data which MarkaVIP may hold or process about you. You have the right to require MarkaVIP to correct any inaccuracies in your data free of charge. At any stage you also have the right to ask us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes by contacting MarkaVIP by email at [support@markavip.com](mailto:support@markavip.com)

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may [correct, update, amend, delete/remove, ask to have it removed from a public forum, directory or testimonial on our site or deactivate it] by making the change on our member information page [or by emailing our Customer Support at [support@markavip.com](mailto:support@markavip.com)

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## 10\. Unsubscribe from newsletter

Since MarkaVIP wants you to stay tuned with MarkaVIP’s fantastic offers, we suggest you to keep your newsletter subscription active, but you can of course unsubscribe from MarkaVIP’s newsletter at any moment.

The easiest way to unsubscribe is to click on the unsubscribe link you receive at the bottom of your daily newsletter, or send an email to [support@markavip.com](mailto:support@markavip.com)

## 11\. Changes to this policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Address: 

Dubai Investment Park LLC  
Plot 598-1298  
Warehouse No. 6  
PO Box 450686  
Dubai UAE
